Preliminary Inventory to the Berton W. Crandall Photographs, 1888-1953
Hoover Institution Archives
- PART 2
  - S-1 to S-249
    - From School of Business through Arch. Also photos of Faculty and interior shots (miscellaneous negatives and print) (Item S-245.)
    - Frenchman's Lake, 1900 (print) (Item S-246.)
    - Frenchman's Lake, 1902 (glass plate) (Item S-246-1.)
    - Library early days (negative) (Item S-246-2.)
    - School of Education (miscellaneous negatives) (Item S-248.)
    - Football teams (two different groups), n.d. (2 negatives) (Item S-249.)
  - S-250 to S-700
    - Industrial Relations meetings in Lagunita Court (miscellaneous negatives) (Item S-250.)
    - "New Library," destroyed in 1906 (negative and print) (Item S-251.)
    - Library Buildings - Earthquake, 1906 (prints) (Item S-251-1 through 5.)
    - "New Library," before 1906 (miscellaneous prints) (Item S-251-6.)
    - Hopkins Room - Library - also portraits (miscellaneous negatives and print) (Item S-252-1.)
    - Street Car - Palo Alto-Stanford Line, 1929-1931 (negative) (Item S-253-1.)
    - University Junction, 1931 at US 101 (negative) (Item S-253-2.)
    - Street Car, 1931 January 30 (negative) (Item S-253-3.)
    - Menlo Park S.P. Railway Station, 1887? (negative) (Item S-254.)
    - Arcade View (negative and print) (Item S-255.)
    - Arcade View (print) (Item S-256.)
    - Arcade View Showing Library (negative and print) (Item S-257.)
    - Arcade View Showing Library (negative and miscellaneous prints) (Item S-259.)
    - Arcade View Physics Corner (negative) (Item S-260.)
    - Arcade View Showing Art Gallery (negative and print) (Item S-261.)
    - Arcade View at Church Entrance showing Class Plates (negative and print) (Item S-262.)
    - Inner Quad and Arcades (glass plate) (Item S-263.)
    - Corner Arches Physics Building (miscellaneous negatives and prints) (Item S-264.)
    - Corner Arches Physics Building with N. Cornell and D. McKee, 1950 March 17 (negatives and prints) (Item S-264-1.)
    - East Arch of Inner Quad from President's office, 1940 (negative and print) (Item S-265.)
    - East Arch of Inner Quad (negative and print) (Item S-266.)
    - Memorial Court Arcades Inner Quad, 1921 (negative and print) (Item S-267.)
    - Memorial Court Arches (glass plate and miscellaneous prints) (Item S-268.)
    - Memorial Arch Front after 1906 earthquake (glass plate and miscellaneous prints) (Item S-269.)
    - Inner Quad (print) (Item S-270.)
    - Memorial Arch Front before 1906 (glass plate) (Item S-271.)
    - Students in Quad, 1930 August (14 miscellaneous negatives and prints) (Item S-272.)
    - Front of Quad before 1906 (glass plate and print) (Item S-273.)
    - Front of Quad (print) (Item S-274.)
    - Quad from Library entrance (negative and print) (Item S-275.)
    - Quad looking through Library Columns (negative and print) (Item S-276.)
    - Quad from Museum before 1906 (glass plate and print) (Item S-277.)
    - Quad from Museum (print) (Item S-278.)
    - Inner Quad looking toward Memorial Court - Two views (negatives and prints) (Item S-279.)
    - Inner Quad (print) (Item S-281.)
    - Inner Quad looking through Memorial Court Arches, 1910 (glass plate and print) (Item S-282.)
    - Inner Quad from Palm Bed (glass plate and print) (Item S-283.)
    - Panorama from roof of Memorial Hall, 1936 December 24 (miscellaneous negatives and prints) (Item S-284.)
    - Main University buildings from Memorial Hall, 1936 (negative) (Item S-285.)
    - Art Gallery from Arcade (negative and similar prints) (Item S-286.)
    - "The Last Spike" (replica) C.P. Railway (from Museum) (negatives and prints) (Item S-288.)
    - Felt Lake Dam construction, completed 1929 December 5 (8 negatives and prints) (Item S-290.)
    - Commencement exercises in Stadium, 1935 June 16 (negative) (Item S-291.)
    - Class plate exercises, 1936 June (miscellaneous negatives) (Item S-291-1.)
    - Graduation Stanford, 1936 June 14 - Tiny Thornhill and football graduates (miscellaneous negatives) (Item S-191-2.)
    - "Stanford University" hand-lettered (negative and print) (Item S-292.)
    - Stanford Book Plate from original drawing (negative and print) (Item S-293.)
    - Stanford Axe on day of recovery, 1930 April 3 - Don Robuskey, Jake Irwin (miscellaneous negatives and picture) (Item S-294.)
    - Production of Elijah in Stadium, 1924 June 8 (miscellaneous negatives and print) (Item S-296.)
    - Stanford New Gateway, 1940 February (negative and print) (Item S-297.)
    - Memorial Arch Front - Earthquake (negative and print) (Item S-301-1.)
    - Memorial Arch Front - Earthquake (glass plate) (Item S-301-1A.)
    - Memorial Church - rebuilding (negative and print) (Item S-301-2.)
    - Fraternity House (negative and print) (Item S-301-3.)
    - Entrance gateway after earthquake (glass plate and print) (Item S-301-4.)
    - Church through shattered arches (glass plate and print) (Item S-301-5.)
    - Church interior (glass plate and print) (Item S-301-6.)
    - Gym and Library (glass plate and print) (Item S-301-7.)
    - "Angel of Grief" - Earthquake 1906 (glass plate and print) (Item S-301-8.)
    - Library (negative and print) (Item S-301-9.)
    - "Angel of Grief" - Earthquake - with Dr. James Cutting (negative and print) (Item S-301-10.)
    - Herbert Hoover Home on campus (negative) (Item S-302.)
    - Exterior front (negative and print) (Item S-302-1.)
    - Exterior north face (negative and print) (Item S-302-2.)
    - Terrace (negative) (Item S-302-3.)
    - Living room (negative and print) (Item S-302-4.)
    - Living room (negative) (Item S-302-5.)
    - Living room fireplace (negative and print) (Item S-302-6.)
    - Roof terrace (negative and print) (Item S-302-7.)
    - Front (negative and print) (Item S-302-8.)
    - Front (negative and print) (Item S-302-9.)
    - Front (negative) (Item S-302-10.)
    - Front (negative) (Item S-302-11.)
    - Herbert Hoover's study (negative) (Item S-302-12.)
    - Herbert Hoover's study (negative) (Item S-302-13.)
    - Front entrance (negative and print) (Item S-302-14.)
    - Dining room (negative) (Item S-302-15.)
    - Dining room (negative) (Item S-302-16.)
    - Stairway (negative and print) (Item S-302-17.)
    - Exterior (negative and print) (Item S-302-18.)
    - Living room fireplace (negative) (Item S-302-19.)
    - Terrace (negative) (Item S-302-20.)
    - Exterior from swimming pool (negative) (Item S-302-21.)
    - Terrace with outdoor fireplace (negative) (Item S-302-22.)
    - Back elevation from Cubberley roof (negative and print) (Item S-302-23.)
    - Front (prints) (Item S-302-24 and 25.)
    - Class plates at church entrance - Dr. Harry B. Reynolds and two men, 1936 October (negative and print) (Item S-303-1.)
    - Class plates at church entrance (negative and print) (Item S-303-2.)
    - Emeritus professors at Allied Arts Guild, 1936 June 4 (negative and print) (Item S-304.)
    - Trees on Lasuen Street (negative) (Item S-305.)
    - Stanford Press Plant, 1935 February (miscellaneous negatives) (Item S-306.)
    - Stanford Planning Department (miscellaneous negatives) (Item S-307.)
    - Mrs. Stanford (glass plate and prints) (Item S-308.)
    - Mr. and Mrs. Stanford from Daguerreotype in Museum - wedding photo (negative and print) (Item S-308-1.)
    - Mrs. Jane Stanford (negative and print) (Item S-308-2.)
    - Leland Stanford Jr. - Copy of a painting (negative and print) (Item S-308-3.)
    - Mrs. Stanford with Leland Stanford Jr. (negative) (Item S-308-4.)
    - Senator Stanford seated with cane (glass plate and 4 prints) (Item S-308-5.)
    - Senator Stanford - Copy of Meissonier Painting, 1881 negative and print) (Item S-308-6.)
    - Mrs. Leland Stanford - Late photograph (glass plate and 4 prints) (Item S-308-7.)
    - Mrs. Leland Stanford, 1889 November (negative) (Item S-308-8.)
    - Mrs. Leland Stanford, 1889 November (negative and print) (Item S-308-8a.)
    - Leland Stanford, 1895 March 26 (negative) (Item S-308-9.)
    - Leland Stanford, 1895 March 26 (negative and print) (Item S-308-9a.)
    - Mrs. Leland Stanford in velvet gown - Paris photo (negative and print) (Item S-308-10.)
    - Leland Stanford Jr. in fur coat and cap with skates (negative and print) (Item S-308-11.)
    - Leland Stanford Sr., 1869 (negative) (Item S-308-12.)
    - Mrs. Stanford - Letters (negatives) (Item S-308-13.)
    - Mrs. Stanford's funeral (3 prints) (Item S-308-14.)
    - Sand Hill Road (print) (Item S-309.)
    - Sand Hill Road (print) (Item S-309-1.)
    - C. K. Jenness (First President of Stanford Alumni Association), 1892, Stanford (negative) (Item S-310.)
    - Stone Carvers at start of buildings (negative and print) (Item S-310-1.)
    - Students-High Wheels, 1896? Encina Steps (negative and print) (Item S-310-2.)
    - Alvarado Row - New Houses (negative and print) (Item S-310-3.)
    - Alvarado Row - New Houses (negative) (Item S-310-3A.)
    - Students in Arcade, 1904? (negative and print) (Item S-310-4.)
    - First Entrance gate (negative and miscellaneous prints) (Item S-310-5.)
    - "Roble Bridge" across San Francisco Creek, 1907 (negative and print) (Item S-310-6.)
    - Inner Quad (glass plate and print) (Item S-310-7.)
    - Church through Arches, 1905 (negative and print) (Item S-310-8.)
    - Campus, 1893 (negative and print) (Item S-310-9.)
    - "Governor's Lane," 1895 (negative and print) (Item S-310-10.)
    - "New Library Building after earthquake (negative and print) (Item S-310-11.)
    - Mausoleum (negative and print) (Item S-310-12.)
    - Dr. Ray L. Wilbur and Dr. T. M. Williams (negative and print) (Item S-310-13.)
    - Roble Hall (negative and print) (Item S-310-14.)
    - Girls in dress of 1894 (negative and print) (Item S-310-15.)
    - Reunion at White House, 1932, Herbert Hoover and others (negative) (Item S-310-16.)
    - Girls' Hair Styles (negative) (Item S-310-17.)
    - Girls in "Plug Ugly" Hats (negative) (Item S-310-18.)
    - Man of 1894 "T.N.E. Group" (negative and print) (Item S-310-21.)
    - Girls on Steps of Roble Hall, about 1891 (negative and print) (Item S-310-22.)
    - Band about 1898 (negative and print) (Item S-310-23.)
    - Football Team, 1895 Varsity - Winners of Berkeley Game (negative and print) (Item S-310-24.)
    - Library Room, 1891 or 1892 (negative and print) (Item S-310-25.)
    - Room in Roble Hall, 1896? (negative and print) (Item S-310-26.)
    - Stanford Family Carriage and Team at Stock Farm, 1896 (negative and print) (Item S-310-27.)
    - Men's Boat House on Lagunita (negative and print) (Item S-310-28.)
    - Studio - Art Class, 1891 or 1892 (negative) (Item S-310-29.)
    - Roble Hall Reception Room, 1891? (negative and print) (Item S-310-30a & b.)
    - Encina Dining Room, 1891 (negative) (Item S-310-31.)
    - Student's room in Encina, 1891 (negative and print) (Item S-310-32.)
    - Men in Front of Encina, 1891 (negative) (Item S-310-33.)
    - Roble Gym (negative and print) (Item S-310-34.)
    - Encina Gym from Encina Hall (negative and print) (Item S-310-35.)
    - "Jolly-up" in Palo Alto Armory, 1910? (negative and print) (Item S-310-36.)
    - "New" Men's Gym, nearly completed and destroyed, 1906 (negative) (Item S-310-37.)
    - "New" Men's Gym, nearly completed and destroyed, 1906 (negative) (Item S-310-38.)
    - "Parade" on Washington's Birthday at Roble, 1912? (negative and print) (Item S-310-39.)
    - Football Rally - Assembly Hall, 1910? (negative and print) (Item S-310-40.)
    - Stanford Crew at Poughkeepsie, N.Y. (negative and print) (Item S-310-41.)
    - Encina Hall construction, 1891 February 7 (negative) (Item S-310-42.)
    - Encina Student in front of Hall after earthquake (negative and print) (Item S-310-43.)
    - Class of 1895 on Encina Hall steps (negative) (Item S-310-44.)
    - Stanford Building construction, 1888 (negative) (Item S-310-45.)
    - Stanford Building construction, 1888 (negative) (Item S-310-45-1.)
    - Stanford Building construction, 1888 (negative) (Item S-310-45-2.)
    - Stanford Building construction, 1888 (negative) (Item S-310-45-3.)
    - Stanford Building construction, 1888 (negative) (Item S-310-45-4.)
    - Stanford Building construction, 1888 (negative) (Item S-310-45-5.)
    - Stanford Building construction, 1888 (negative) (Item S-310-45-6.)
    - Stanford Building construction, 1888 (negative) (Item S-310-45-7.)
    - Stanford Building construction, 1888 (negative) (Item S-310-45-8.)
    - Stanford Building construction, 1888 (negative) (Item S-310-45-9.)
    - Quad from Museum, 1898 or earlier (negative) (Item S-310-46.)
    - Photos for Stanford Library reports from 1939 (miscellaneous negatives, also copies of paintings) (Item S-311.)
    - Buildings from Museum roof, 1940 October 31 (negative and print) (Item S-312.)
    - Hoover Library - Northeast corner view (negative and print) (Item S-313.)
    - Hoover Tower under construction (prints) (Item S-313a.)
    - Hoover Library, night-lighted, 50th year, 1941 June 19 (negative and print) (Item S-313-1.)
    - Hoover Library (night?) (Item S-313-1a.)
    - Hoover Library - With Art Gallery (negative and print) (Item S-313-2.)
    - Hoover Library - Above trees (negative and print) (Item S-313-3.)
    - Hoover Library - With Education Building (negative and print) (Item S-313-4.)
    - Hoover Library - From church, with clouds, 1951 (negative and print) (Item S-313-5.)
    - Hoover Library - Contributors' names in Lobby, 1945 October 4 (negative) (Item S-313-6.)
    - Hoover Library - Through arches (negative and print) (Item S-313-7.)
    - Hoover Library - Through arches (negative and print) (Item S-313-8.)
    - Hoover Library - From Quad (negative and print) (Item S-313-9.)
    - Hoover Library - From Quad, 1942 (negative and print) (Item S-313-10.)
    - Hoover Library - Lobby Gates (negative and print) (Item S-313-11a.)
    - Hoover Library - Lobby Gates (negative and print) (Item S-313-11b.)
    - Hoover Library - From Church (negative) (Item S-313-12.)
    - Hoover Library - First World War Group: Mc Cormick, Auchincloss, Col. House, Davis, Shepherdson, Lamont (standing) - Robinson, Baruch, Adm. Benson, Gen. Bliss, Herbert Hoover - seated (negative) (Item S-313-13.)
    - Hoover Library - Best front view (negative and print) (Item S-313-14.)
    - Hoover Library - Bells arrival, 1941 June 8 (negative) (Item S-313-15.)
    - Hoover Library - Bells arrival (print) (Item S-314-5.)
    - Hoover Library - Bells arrival (print) (Item S-314-6.)
    - Stanford Chemistry Staff, 1941 March 10 (negative and print) (Item S-315.)
    - Views from Lathrop Hill looking across Lagunita (negative and print) (Item S-317-1.)
    - Views from Lathrop Hill looking across Lagunita (negative and print) (Item S-317-2.)
    - Toyon and Branner Halls from Library Tower (negative and print) (Item S-317-3.)
    - Students - Main Library stairs, 1941 September (negative and print) (Item S-318.)
    - Dr. Don Tresidder portrait (negative and print) (Item S-320.)
    - Dr. Don Tresidder portrait (negative) (Item S-321.)
    - Dr. Don Tresidder portrait (negative and print) (Item S-322.)
    - Dr. Don Tresidder portrait (print) (Item S-322-1.)
    - Stanford Faculty and Staff (miscellaneous prints) (Item S-323.)
    - Medical School - Ruth Stern Research Building, San Francisco (negative) (Item S-324.)
    - Ruth Stern - Miscellaneous photographs (negatives and prints) (Item S-324-1.)
    - Art Gallery - Paintings by Frank Brangyn and Keith. Also Leventritt Collection, 1947 December 14 (negative) (Item S-326.)
    - Leland Stanford Home - Early home in the East near Albany, N.Y. (negative) (Item S-327-1.)
    - Leland Stanford Home - San Francisco (negative and 2 prints) (Item S-327-2.)
    - Leland Stanford Home - San Francisco (negative) (Item S-327-3.)
    - Leland Stanford Home - San Francisco - Drawing Room (negative) (Item S-327-4.)
    - Leland Stanford Home - San Francisco - Library (negative) (Item S-327-5.)
    - Leland Stanford Home - San Francisco - Picture Gallery (negative) (Item S-327-6.)
    - Leland Stanford Home - San Francisco - Dining Room (negative) (Item S-327-7.)
    - Leland Stanford Home - San Francisco (negative) (Item S-327-8.)
    - Leland Stanford Home - San Francisco (negative) (Item S-327-9.)
    - Leland Stanford Home - San Francisco - Mrs. Stanford's bedroom (negative) (Item S-327-10.)
    - Leland Stanford Home - Palo Alto (negative and print) (Item S-327-11.)
    - Leland Stanford Home - Palo Alto - President and Mrs. Benjamin Harrison, and Mr. and Mrs. Stanford in carriage (negative) (Item S-327-12.)
    - Leland Stanford Home - Palo Alto - Dining Room (negative and print) (Item S-327-13.)
    - Leland Stanford Home - Sacramento (glass plate and miscellaneous prints) (Item S-327-14.)
    - Leland Stanford Home - Palo Alto - Exterior, miscellaneous views (negative and prints) (Item S-327-15.)
    - Leland Stanford Home? - Old Mining Town Store (glass plate) (Item S-327-16.)
    - Herbert Hoover and Dr. Sterling on Herbert Hoover's 75th birthday, 1949 August (negative and print) (Item S-328.)
    - Dr. Sterling (print) (Item S-328-1.)
    - Agassiz Statue after falling from the upper front of building, 1906 April 18 earthquake. It was told that Dr. Jordan remarked that Professor Agassiz was better in the abstract than in the concrete. Eventually the statue was pulled out and returned to its pedestal, unharmed (negatives and prints) (Item S-330-1 through 5.)
    - Start of Building - Stanford University (negative) (Item S-601.)
    - Start of Building - Stanford University (negative) (Item S-601-1.)
    - Breaking ground for Stanford University (negative) (Item S-602.)
    - Church site about 1896? (negative and print) (Item S-603.)
    - Working on Church front - Original construction (negative and print) (Item S-603-1.)
    - Stone carving in Church - Work usually done after the masons had finished setting the stone in place (negative and print) (Item S-603-2.)
    - Quad from Alvarado Row (negative and print) (Item S-604.)
    - Early Stanford Quad from Encina Hall roof (negative) (Item S-605.)
    - Campus from top of Church looking out Lasuen Street about 1904 (negative and print) (Item S-606.)
    - Stanford Seal (negative) (Item S-609.)
    - Stanford Plates - Spode, 1935 December (negative) (Item S-610.)
    - Miscellaneous prints (2 unidentified photographs of homes) (Item S-700.)